Let's learn about Bob Operation and stack removing any element from the top of the stack is called up.
Consider this stack.
We have these elements that we have pushed them in the previous video or we have inserted it in the
stack one, two and three.
The top level of the stop element of these elements is three.
So if we are going to pop the elements we need to pop, then the elements starting from the top.
So if we execute the method pop, we are going to pop the city.
We are removing the element from the stack at the top.
We are not going to remove no one.
We are going to remove that top level element, which is three.
Now, if we execute again, it will remove two.
And if we remove and we execute it again, it was removed one from this stack.
OK, now let's stop data from a stack by using the code.
OK, consider this code and consider a stack here.
Remember, we are making a stack here using the arrays, and in the next videos, we are going to make
a stack using linked list.
So what data from is stack?
We consider making an array here.
Array at Index two, array at index one and then rate at index zero.
OK.
We have created the array in the previous videos and this stack using the array.
So now let's go and pop if top equal equal to minus one.
We are checking the top is if it is minus one.
Then the stack is empty.
Else print f bob element and we printed again, OK?
And top minus minus, so with decreased by one.
Let's see.
By animation how it works.
And then we are going to see it in the in real exercise.
Let's pop.
This is the top.
It's referring to that we have pushed the elements 100, 200 and 300.
Now let's execute the method up.
So what are the elements now from the stack?
We are going to remove 300 and we have removed that.
OK, now let's pop 200.
We remove it from the stack and.
Remove its current element.
Let's go to the last one and execute the top pop element pop element from the stack, we remove it.
And here we go.
We have emptying the stack.
OK, now.
Topic equals minus one, it referred that the stack is empty.
You see here the algorithm behind popping, it's just removing the element from the stack.
Now.
This situation about behind making the top two, one zero and minus one, and we are removing and popping
the elements that we have learned is in worse and is costing time, complexity in the worst case is
of one and the best gates is of one.
Yes.
This is why Stack is very important if you have a very important data structure, if you have things
that you are going to add them as a pile, OK, so you whenever you have any problem or anything that
you can think of the stack data structure as the pile of plate on the top of another.
Then you can use the stack because it's very important and very fast in inserting and pushing and popping
data from a stack.
OK.
Because the time complexity will give you one.
And the best case and in the.